You ever sit down to write the first
draft of something and find
yourself spending more time
editing or playing whack-a-mole with
squiggly red lines? That
stuff drives me crazy. It's so
distracting. So I created Wastebasket, a
super simple writing app
designed just for drafting
words. Here's how it works. You open
wastebasket.app and you
start writing. That's it.
Wastebasket won't try to help you.
There's no spell check,
auto-complete, or AI tools. You can't
even make something bold. It gets out of
your way so you can focus
on the words you're currently
trying to write. Put it in full screen
for a completely Zen
experience. When you're done,
click copy or save it to your device. If
you want to start over, just toss the
current draft in the
wastebasket. Oh look, there's some
settings. Let's check them out. You can
pick from one of three
fonts. I figure any more choices than
that and you're just procrastinating.
We've also got themes,
light, dark, and auto. You can even move
the toolbar to the top. I
find that useful for writing
on the iPad. Do you want an icon to click
on? You can add to dock  or
add to home screen or some
browsers have an install option. There
you go. Wastebasket stores
everything on your device.
Nothing is stored in the cloud and
there's no accounts and no tracking
either. It even works
when you're offline. How cool is that?
All right, enough
already. Go write something.